《星际传奇》
听说被冷冻后脑活动几乎全停
They say most of your brain shuts down in cryo-sleep.
只有原始野性没停
All but the primitive side
那就是兽性
the animal side.
所以我还醒着
No wonder I'm still awake.
我与平民混在一起
Transporting me with civilians...
好像有40多人
Sounded like forty, forty-plus.
听到阿拉伯人讲话
Heard an Arab voice.
一个失意的圣人
Some hoodoo holy man...
可能是去新麦加朝圣
Probably on his way to New Mecca...
可是走哪条路？哪条路？
But what route? What route?
闻到女人味…
Smelled a woman...
汗臭 靴子 工具带的皮革味
sweat, boots, tool belt, leather,
典型的
prospector type
自由迁徙者
Free settlers.
他们专找偏僻的小路
And they only take the back roads
接下来这位是我的难题
And here's my real problem.
强斯先生
Mr. Johns...
蓝眼珠的魔鬼
Blue eyed devil...
打算押我回去坐牢
plannin' on takin' me back to slam.
不过他这次遇到鬼了
Only this time he picked a ghost lane
往鬼门关的路很长
A long time between stops...
所以夜长梦多
A long time for something to go wrong.
(紧急 船身破裂)
(导航系统)
(40个冷冻柜运作正常)
(苏醒)
(死亡)
我怎么会坠落？
Why did I fall on you?
他死了 船长死了
He's dead. The Captain's dead.
我看着他死的
I was looking night at him.
仪器显示我们已过了22周
The chrono shows we are 22 weeks out
但是再过19周才有引力
so gravity was not supposed to kick in for another 19.
我怎么会坠落？
Why'd I fall at all?
听到没有？我说船长死了
Did you hear what I said? Captain's dead.
1550豪巴
1550 millibars.
每秒钟下降20豪巴
Dropping 20 MB per minute.
可恶 舱压外泄 我们被什么东西扫到
Shit! We're hemorrhaging air. Something took a swipe at us.
快说 我们还在航道上
Come on. Just tell me we're still in the shipping lane.
给我看那些巨星
Just show me all those stars.
快点 又大又亮的星星
Come on! Those big bright.
什么？
What?
这里是猎人号商船紧急求救
This is an emergency dispatch from merchant vessel Hunter Gratzner
航向丹吉尔星系
en route to the Tangier system
有40名乘客 偏离航道
with 40 commercial passengers on board.
正在进入…
We have been knocked out of our shipping lane,
一个有大气的行星
and are currently entering the atmosphere of a planetary body
位置是X38-5 Y95-8… Z21
in the following position X38-stroke-five. Y95-stroke-eight... Z21
弗莱 怎么没有通讯？
Fry, where the hell's our Comms?
下降率无法计算
Rate of descent, beyond known limits.
弗莱 你受过训耶
Hey, they trained you for this, Fry, right?
(气压刹车)
(放气压刹车)
引力中心在船尾
Center of gravity too far aft
建议立刻抛弃压舱物
Recommend purging ballast now.
干嘛…要丢东西 弗莱？
What the... Was that a purge, Fry?
船尾太重
Too heavy in the ass.
船头拉不下去
Can't get my fucking nose down.
启用2号应急系统
Crisis program selected Number Two in this system
球面地形最高220公尺
Maximum terrain 220 meters over mean surface
有火山渣石膏 挥发性沉淀物
largely cinder and gypsum with some evaporate deposits.
弗莱 你搞什么鬼？
Fry, what the hell are you doing?
多丢一些东西
I gotta drop more load.
我都试过了 还是不见地平线
Look, I tried everything else. I still got no horizon.
你最好多试两次
Well, you better try everything twice
欧文 你比我行你来呀
If you know something I don't, get up here and take the chair.
公司要我们负责每个人的安全
Listen, Company says we are responsible for every single one of those people, Fry.
为了负责就得卖命吗？
We both die out of sheer fucking nobility?
弗莱 不要碰那把柄
Don't you touch that handle, Fry.
我不要为他们牺牲
I'm not gonna die for them.
- 气门没有关紧  - 欧文
- Airlock doors not secured.  - Owens!
你还有70秒把船身拉平
Seventy seconds. Fry! You still have seventy seconds to level this beast out.
放气压刹车
Deploy lower airbrakes now
上面搞什么鬼？
What the fuck is happening up there?
(系统警报)
伊曼
Imam?
对 伊曼
Yeah, Imam.
齐克
Zeke?
(紧锁 不可提早放开)
早晚会有人受伤
Somebody's gonna get hurt one of these days.
不会是我
It ain't gonna be me.
给你 夏沙
Here, Shazza.
所以…我猜是出了错
So, I guess something went wrong?
欧文
Owens.
对不起
I'm sorry.
帮我拨出来
Get it outta me.
不要碰
Don't touch it!
不要碰那把柄
Don't you touch that handle!
- 别碰它  - 帮他拨出来
- Leave it alone.  - Get it out of him.
不 不 不 太靠近心脏了
No... It's too close to his heart.
后舱医务室还有麻醉剂
There's some Anestaphine in the med-lock in the back of the cabin.
没有了
Not anymore there's not.
大家都出去
Get out of here. Everyone.
出去
Get out of here.
我上了免费飞行课
That'll teach me for flying coach.
有意思
Interesting.
还有谁呼吸有困难？
Is anyone else having difficulties breathing?
我就像少了一片肺 大家都是
Yeah. I feel one lung short. All of us.
好像刚刚跑完步
Feel like I just ran or something.
听说搜索队在找人
There was talk of a scouting party looking for other people
怎么回事？
What the bloody hell happened?
可能是流星风暴
Could have been a meteor storm.
也可能是慧星 不一定
Might have been a rogue comet I don't know.
至少我个人感激不尽
Well, I for one am thoroughly grateful.
这样降落难度极高 不过…
This beast wasn't made to land like this, but...
你做得很好
I think you did well.
我们能活着全靠她
Actually, the only reason we're alive is because of her.
你说得对 多谢你
Yes, I suppose you're right. Thanks very much.
对 多谢救我们的老命
Yeah. Thanks for saving our dicks.
不 真的感谢
No, really thanks, awfully.
干得好
Well done.
他刚逃出戒备森严的监狱
He just escaped from a maximum prison.
要永远把他锁住吗？
So do we just keep him locked up forever?
我赞成
That'd be my choice.
他真的很凶猛？
Is he really that dangerous?
对人很凶猛
Only around humans.
货舱整个翻覆 里面一团糟
The whole bloody container's upside down. It's all topsy-turvy.
感谢上帝 没有全部完蛋
Thank goodness it's not a total loss.
酒？只有喝这玩意了？
Booze? This is what you have to drink?
拿酒要写收据
I'm gonna need a receipt for that.
这些都要 这是我的私人物品
For all of this. This is my personal stuff.
这对你没有用吧？
I don't suppose this'll help you at all?
可惜朝圣时禁酒
Unfortunately, it is not permitted Especially while on hajj.
这里没有水你知道吗？
You do realize there's no water, don't you?
所有沙漠都有水 只需要多找找
All deserts have water. It only waits to be found.
希望如此
I hope you're right.
我更希望
All the more for me, then.
这是什么玩意？
And what the h ell are these?
北印度的兵器 很稀有
Martha crow-bill war-picks from Northern India. Very rare.
这个呢？
And this?
巴布亚新几内亚飞针筒
That's a hunting blow-dart pipe from Papua New Guinea.
非常非常罕见 因部落早灭亡了
And that's very, very rare, since the tribe is now extinct.
大概因为不懂如何使用这些武器吧
'Cause they couldn't hunt shit with these things would be my guess.
管他的 反正灭种了
What's the point anyway? If the man is gone, he's gone.
何必烦心？
Why should he bother us?
或许他会来抢你的东西
Maybe to take what you got.
又或者吓吓你
Maybe to work your nerves.
又或者趁你睡觉时对付你
Or maybe to just come back and skull-fuck you in your sleep.
听起来很神秘
He sounds like a charmer.
只是对你来说
For you.
去看看… 出发吧
Let's just see. There we go. Yeah.
- 可以吗？- 可以
- Yeah?  - Yeah.
伊曼
Imam.
如果要找水早点动身
If we're looking for water, we should leave soon.
到天黑时会很冷
Before nightfall while it's cooler.
阿里
Ali.
对不起
Excuse me.
你看看这个
I think you should see this.
三个太阳？
Three suns?
真要命
Bloody hell.
天黑不了啦
So much for you nightfall.
鸡尾酒报销了
So much for my cocktail hour.
这是好兆头
We take this as a good sign
神指引我们一条路
a path, direction from Allah.
蓝色的太阳 蓝色的水
Blue sun, blue water.
知道我为何不信神吗？
Every wondered why I'm an atheist?
这是坏兆头 那是瑞迪的方向
It's a bit of a bad sign. That's Riddick's direction.
他不可能朝日落方向走
I thought you found his restraints over there. Toward sunset.
他只会向日出走
Right. Which means he went toward sunrise.
齐克
Zeke.
上满子弹 一见他便开枪
Fully loaded clip... safety's on... One shot if you spot him, okay?
- 难道你也要去？- 对
- Don't tell me you're going off too  - Yeah.
假如瑞迪先发现我们呢？
But what happens if Mr. Riddick spots us first?
那你就没机会开枪了
That would be no shots.
安静
Quiet.
七块石头困住魔鬼
Seven stones to keep the devil at bay.
你正要去新麦加吧
You're on a trip to New Mecca, right?
一生就一次 那就应该是很神圣的
Once in every lifetime, should there be a great hajj.
麦加朝圣
A great pilgrimage.
更好地了解真主阿拉
To get to know Allah better?
也更了解你自己
Yes, but to know yourself, as well.
嗯
Yeah.
我们都在麦加朝圣
We are all on the same hajj now.
抱歉
Sorry.
有什么发现？
So did you see anything?
没有瑞迪的迹象
No Riddick.
树 有树就有水
Trees. And trees mean water.
在上面舒服吗？
You comfy up there?
非常舒服 很惊讶在没有生活必需品的时候
Yes, it's amazing how you can do without the necessities of life
还能有这样的小小奢侈
provided you have the little luxuries.
好了 眼睛放亮一点
Well, just keep your bloody eyes open.
我可不想被他偷袭
I don't want that dog sneaking up on my bloody ass.
你挖你的墓 我放我的哨
You dig the graves. I'll hold the fort, old boy.
老天
Christ!
他可能会在你那里划一刀
He'd probably get you right here, right under the jaw
无声无息就是瑞迪的绝招
and you'd never even hear him coming.
告诉我 是你抛弃了你父母还是父母不要你？
Tell me something, did you run away from your parents or did they run away from you?
这里或许是坟场 像地球的象坟
It's a communal graveyard perhaps, like the elephants of Earth.
他问是什么有这种杀伤力
He asks what could have killed so many great things.
这个星球死光了吗？
Is this whole planet dead?
喝吗？
Drink?
它让你脱水得更厉害
Probably shouldn't do this Dehydrates you even more.
你说得也对
You're probably right.
你可以留在船上 应该留下
You know, you could've stayed back at the ship. Probably should've.
挖不到水就惨了
If we don't find water, you know what happens.
我想离开
I wanted to get away.
没见过急着要弃船的船长
I've never seen a captain so ready to leave her ship.
我们应该往前走
I think we should keep moving.
欧文说别碰把柄是为什么？
What did Owens mean about not touching the handle?
我不乱讲 卡洛琳 我保证
It's just between you and me, Carolyn. I promise.
我不是船长
I'm not your captain.
着陆的时候
During the landing,
情况最恶劣时欧文表现最好
when things were at their worst, Owens was at his best.
他阻止了机师放弃主船舱
He's the one that stopped the docking pilot from dumping the main cabin.
那些乘客
The passengers.
那个机师是…
And the docking pilot being?
来这里的心情比想像中快乐
I guess I'm a little more glad to be here than I thought.
哈珊 苏利曼
Hassan' Suleman.
船长
Captain.
这里有人吗？
Is there anyone here?
以前这里有水
There was water here.
灯
Lights.
开灯
Lights on.
好
Okay.
意思是伟大的神 是的
They are saying "God is great". Allahu Akbar, yes.
这是水源
This is the source of the water.
没有黑暗
No darkness.
没有灯 因为没有黑暗
No lights because no darkness.
你好 麦加
Hello, Mecca.
刚才是你吧
Tell me that was you just now.
胡说什么？他一直在帮我
What are you going on about? He's been right here helping me.
船尾有声音
Back of the ship. That noise.
难道还有别人？
You trying to tell me that was someone else?
不要
No!
我的天
Oh my God.
我以为只有我生还
I thought I was the only one who got out of the crash alive.
是另一个人
It's just somebody else.
不过是个生还者
It was just somebody else from the crash.
我还以为是他
Crikey. I thought it was him.
我以为是瑞迪
I thought it was Riddick.
没电 看来荒废多年了
No juice. It looks like it's been laid up for years.
不过我也许可以用它…
But we might be able to adapt it to...
安静
Shut up.
抱歉 我以为有声音
Sorry, I thought I heard something.
什么声音？
Like what?
枪声
Gunshots.
齐克
Zeke!
狗屎
Piece of shit.
你把齐克怎么了？
What did you do to Zeke?
- 你把他怎么了？- 夏沙
- What did you do to him?  - Shazza.
快杀他 以免他再害人
Just kill him! Just somebody goddam kill him before he...
尸体在哪里？
So where's the body?
谈谈你听到的声音
Well, do you want to tell me about this sounds?
你跟强斯说听到声音
You told Johns you heard something.
没关系
That's fine.
不说随便你 但你要知道
You don't want to talk to me, that's your choice. But just so you know.
大家在讨论是否留下你等死
There's a debate right now as to whether we should just leave you here to die.
你是说那一阵耳语
You mean the whispers?
什么耳语？
What whispers?
那声音要我对脊椎左侧下手
The ones telling me to go for the sweet spot
第四节下方腹部大动脉
fourth lumbar down. The abdominal aorta.
有金属味的人血
It's a metallic taste, human blood.
但是配薄荷酒就容易下肚
Copperish, but if you cut it with peppermint schnapps,that goes away quickly.
你想吓我？
You wanna shock me with the truth now?
你们都很怕我
All you people are so scared of me.
平时我会觉得很得意
Most days I'd take that as a compliment.
但你们现在要怕的不是我
But ain't me you gotta worry about now.
瑞迪 让我看看你的眼睛
Show me your eyes, Riddick.
你得站近一点才行
You'd have to come a lot closer for that.
再近一点…
Closer...
你从哪弄来这双眼？
Where the hell can I get eyes like that?
要杀几个人
You gotta kill a few people.
杀人我会
Okay. I can do it.
然后去蹲黑牢
Then you gotta get sent to a slam
他们会让你永不见天日
where they tell you you'll never see daylight again.
你找一个医生
You dig up a doctor
给他二十根薄荷香烟
and you pay him 20 menthol Kools
动手术使你的眼珠发光
to do a surgical shine job on your eyeballs.
所以你看见暗中的偷袭者？
So you can see who's sneaking up on you in the dark?
不错
Exactly.
走开
Leave!
可爱的小伙子
Cute kid.
我杀过几个人吗？
Did I kill a few people?
当然
Sure.
我杀了齐克？
Did I kill Zeke?
不对 你找错人了
No, you got the wrong killer.
他不在洞里 我们找过
He's not in the hole. We looked.
深入一点找
Look deeper.
我告诉你我的想法吧
Let me tell you what I think happened.
我想他把那家伙埋在某处
I think he went off on the guy, buried him in the hills.
他要你相信还有其他东西
Now he's got you believing there's something there.
让我们去确定一下
Well, let's just be sure.
瑞迪是个著名杀手
Look, murders aside, Riddick belongs in the asshole hall of fame.
他喜欢让你害怕
He loves to jaw-jack and loves to make you feel afraid,
他就是那样的 而你正往虎穴里走
because that's all he has. You're playing right into it.
我为什么要跟你解释这些
Why try to explain this to you?
你是警察 我们要找到他尸体
You're a cop. For God's sake, we've got to find his body.
我要去
Hey! I'll go.
都不能去
Look, no one is going.
呆在这儿
Stay here.
逞英雄并不改变什么 而且这很蠢
Look, being ballsy with your life, doesn't change what came before. It's stupid.
你觉得我想证明什么吗？
What, do you think I'm trying to prove something?
你有吗？
Well, are you?
我在这里
I'm in here.
我在这里 在洞里
I'm in here! I'm inside!
我好像听到声音
I thought I heard something.
听见我吗？
Please. Can you hear me?
我在这里 在洞里
I'm in here. I'm inside.
把手伸过来
Give me your goddam hand!
我听到了 我先听到的
I heard you, Fry. I heard you first.
弗莱 你要紧吗？
Fry... You okay?
洞里有什么？怎么回事？
What's down there? What is it?
- 找到齐克没有？- 你没事了
- You're all right.  - Did you find Zeke?
弗莱 要紧吗？
Fry, you okay?
- 我很好  - 可恶
- Okay.  - Fuck.
那真的笨死了
That was so fucking stupid.
我不知道洞里是什么
I don't know what the fuck is in there
但它害了锡基 我也差点…
but whatever it is, it got Zeke and it nearly go me...
帮我解开
Get it off me.
小心
Watch it.
- 帮我解开  - 当心头
- Get it off me.  - Watch your head.
终于遇到比我可怕的东西了
Finally found something worse than me, huh?
我们来个协议
so here's the deal.
你可以不戴锁链和小刀受苦
You work without chains, without the bit, and without shivs
但你一举一动要听我的
You do what I say, when I say it.
为什么？
For what?
要跟你回牢房？去你的
The honor of going back to some asshole of a cell. Fuck you.
老实说我已厌倦追捕你了
The truth is, I'm tired of chasing you.
你是说你可以放我走？
Are you saying you'd cut me loose?
你本该在意外中死掉
I'm thinking you could have died in the crash.
我建议你杀了我
My recommendation: Do me.
不要冒被我捅一刀的危险
Don't take the chance that I'll get shiv-happy on your wannabe ass
好吧
Okay.
杀了我 因为我会杀你
Ghost me, motherfucker. That's what I would do to you.
我要你记住这一刻
I want you to remember this moment.
本来该死却没死
The way it coulda gone and didn't.
拿去
Here.
去你的
Fuck you.
一言为定是吗？
Do we have a deal?
我要你记住这一刻
I want you to remember this moment.
- 只有一个？- 目前一个
- Just one?  - For now.
强斯
Johns...
你一弹指他就投效我们
So you click your fingers, and he's one of us now.
我没说 至少现在没必要担心
I didn't say that.At least this way I don't have to worry about y'all, uh,
你们睡得像死猪
falling asleep and not waking up.
可以跟他说话吗？
So could I talk to him now?
不行
No.
可恶
Blast!
奥格尔维
Paris P. Ogilvie.
古董商
Antiquities dealer entrepreneur.
理查德·B·瑞迪
Richard B Riddick.
逃亡的杀人犯
Escaped convict murderer
上好的喜拉兹 好酒
That's a particularly good Shiraz. It's a lovely drop.
这酒很贵 尽量喝 别客气
It's... It's very expensive. By all means, please help yourself.
我一般很欣赏古董
I mean, normally I can appreciate antiques.
但这不同
But this, this is something else.
会有用的
It'll work.
只要有电 没有什么修不了的
It's nothing we can't repair, so long as the electrical adapts.
这可不是跨越障碍赛
It's not a star-jumper.
不需要
It doesn't need to be.
我们很快会回到海洋航线
Take a 2-seater like this back up to the Sol-Track shipping lanes.
伸出大拇指
Stick out her thumb,
就能搭顺风车
bound to get picked up.
对吗？船长？
Ain't that right, captain?
谁可以帮我？
Can I have a little help here?
我来
I got it. Come on.
帮我个忙
Do me a favor.
看看那些集装箱
Check these containers out and, uh,
看看如何修好这些飞翼
see what we can patch these wings up with.
好吗？
All right?
好 该我了
All right, all right, my turn.
(飞行控制策略)
我们真的到那边了
We really are getting there.
动力够检查系统用 但还要电池
We've got enough power for sys-check, but we still need more cells.
还要多少？
How many are we talking about?
我们要90 另一艘船要20
We got a 90 gig draw, the other ship takes 20 gig cells.
- 五个电池  - 升空要五个电池
- That'd be five.  - Five total to launch.
每个35公斤？
Thirty-five kilos each, huh?
那确实很重
Well, that's pretty heavy.
你看见在那边的小车么？
You know that old sand cat out there?
我也许能让它动
I might be able to get it going.
试试吧 需要帮忙吗？
Do it if you can. But if you need a hand.
瑞迪上哪去了？
Where'd Riddick go?
我们走
Let's go.
你错过热闹了 快走
You're missing the party. C'mon, boy.
错过热闹了 快
Missing the party. Come on.
该死的
Oh, man.
感谢真神的眷顾
All praises be Allah, for his many blessings to us.
什么？
What?
这是超级模仿秀的优胜者
It's the winner of the look-alike contest.
这些是什么人？矿工？
Who were these people anyway? Miners?
好像是地质学家
It looks like Geologists.
一支先遣队 探堪岩石
You know, an advance team, moves around from rock to rock.
幸好他们留下许多东西
Nice of them to leave so much stuff here.
他们为什么弃船？
Why'd they leave their ship?
不是船 而是可丢弃的小艇
It's not a ship, it's a skiff, and it's disposable really.
更像是救生艇吧？
It's more like an emergency life-raft, right?
对 可能是乘大登陆艇走了
Yeah, they probably had a big drop ship take 'em off planet.
这些人没有走
These people didn't leave. Come on.
杀齐克的东西杀了他们
Whatever got Zeke, got them. They're all dead.
他们会丢下衣物走吗？
You don't really think they left with their clothes on hooks,
照片也没带走
photos on the shelves...
说不定行李重量有限制
Maybe they had weight limits. You don't know.
不是紧急不会用逃生艇
I know you don't prep your emergency ship unless there's a fucking emergency.
他讲得对
He's fucking right.
闭嘴
Watch your mouth.
他说出我们的想法
Hey, he's just saying what we're all thinking.
怎么回事？他们人呢？
So what happened? Where are they?
有谁见到阿里？
Has anyone seen the little one? Ali?
去样品室找过没有？
Has anyone checked the coring room?
阿里
Ali.
Ali?
- 慢慢来  - 杰克 等等
- Slowly. Take your time.  - Jack, wait. Wait.
阿里
Ali?
伊曼
Imam?
其他建筑不安全
Other building weren't secure.
这儿的门很厚重
So they ran here. Heaviest doors.
他们以为在这里就安全
Thought they'd be safe inside.
却忘了锁地窖门
But they forgot to lock the cellar.
给你
Here.
怎么了？坏了？
What, it's broken?
还有一些
No. There's still a few hits.
事实上我想跟你说 我很抱歉
Actually, you asshole. I'm trying to say that I'm sorry.
好了 让我们离开这里
Ok, let's board this place up and get the hell out of here.
无论那是什么
Whatever the fuck those things were,
它们喜欢躲在暗处
they seem to stick to darkness,
白天行动就没事
so if we stick to daylight we should be all right, okay?
我们走
Let's go.
二十二年前
Twenty two years ago.
什么？
What?
这些样本的日期
These coring samples are dated.
最后一个的日期是二十二年前
Last one's twenty two years ago this month.
这有什么特别？
Okay. Is there something special about that, Carolyn?
不知道 或许有古怪
I don't know. There could be.
日蚀
An eclipse.
你不怕黑吧？
You're not afraid of the dark, are you?
一定要找能源
So we've gotta get the power cells.
糟糕 还要检查船身修补机翼
Shit, I've still gotta check on the hull and patch the wings.
我们要等找到能源
Wait on the power cells.
等什么？等到天黑就认不到路了
Wait for what? 'Til it's so dark we can't even find our way back?
防不胜防 别冲动
You don't know when it's gonna happen, so let's not get overexcited.
快拿电池来 讨论什么？
Just get the fucking cells here, Johns. What... What is the discussion?
我应该讲瑞迪逃亡的情形
Maybe I should tell you how Riddick escaped.
他会驾船
He can pilot.
他劫持囚船逃亡
He hijacked a prison transport
被我猎捕
and made a hell of a good run before tracked his ass down.
这也许是好事
Okay, maybe that's a good thing.
他可协助导航
Maybe we can use him to help us navigate or something.
但他会干掉机师
He also figured out how to kill the pilot.
你说过我们可以信他
You told me that we could trust him. You said that we had a deal, Johns.
你应该注意到了 链子锁不住他
Now you may have noticed, but chains don't work on this guy.
他觉得自由你们才会安全
The only way you people are truly safe is if he believes he's going free.
假如他不这样想…
Let's just say he stops believing...
你是说他若发觉被利用
You mean if he realizes that we're gonna royally fuck him over.
能否听我说一句？
I want you to just listen to me for a second.
如果最后一刻拿电池来
If we bring the cells up at the last possible minute,
等机翼修理好要升空时…
when the wings are ready and when we're ready to launch...
他没有伤人
He hasn't hammed any of us.
也没有骗我们
As far as I can tell, he hasn't even lied to us.
我们就遵守协议
Let's just stick to the deak, Johns.
他是杀人犯
He's a killer!
法律要他服刑 我没办法
And the law says he has to do his bid.
明白吗？
You hear me?
你这是在冒险
You're dancing on razor blades here.
我不会让他再劫船
I'm not gonna give him a chance to grab another ship
或是割驾驶的喉咙
or slash another pilot's throat.
有我在他休想
Not on my watch.
情况不妙
Bad sign.
这种热度下抖成这样
Shaking like that in this heat.
我说过不准用刀
I thought I said no shivs.
这玩意？
This?
这个只是给我个人剃须用的
This is just a personal grooming appliance.
谢谢
Thanking you.
看来我们有点害羞
Looks like we're a few shy.
电池
Power cells.
他们来了
They're coming.
怎么还没有测试驱动主机
It's strange, not doing a run-up on the main drive yet.
除非…
Unless...
他告诉你
Unless he told you...
我逃亡的事
the particulars of my escape.
简单丑陋的版本
I got the quick and ugly version.
你担心历史会重演？
Now you're wormed about a repeat of history?
有过这念头
It has entered our minds.
我问你的想法
I asked what you thought.
你吓着我了
You scare me Riddick.
这就是你想听的吧
That's what you want to hear, isn't it?
我可以做事了吗？
Now, can I just get back to work?
我一直想跟你单独谈
I've been meaning to catch up with you alone.
不戴锁链
Unrestrained.
你认为强斯正直？
You think Johns is a do-night man?
我可以相信他会放了我？
You think I can trust him to cut me loose?
怎么？你听到什么？
Why? What did you hear?
这个…
Well...
假如他要使诈何不干脆杀我 他不会手软
Guess if it was trickeration, he'd just "X" me out, huh? He'd kill me.
所以我活着比死更值钱
Then again, I am worth twice as much alive.
哦 我想你不知道吧？
Oh, you didn't know that?
强斯不是警察
Your Johns ain't a cop.
他有警徽
He's got that nickle-slick badge.
也有蓝色制服
And that blue uniform.
但他是赏金猎人
But he's just a merc.
他要拿我领悬赏
And I'm just a payday.
所以他不杀我 因为贪财
That's why he won't kill me, see? The creed is greed...
别浪费我的时间
Don't waste my time.
你怎么说我们都不对胃口
We're not gonna turn on each other no matter how hard you try.
卡洛琳 天黑之后很难说
I don't truly know what's gonna happen when the lights go out Carolyn.
但是我知道 当真正的死亡来临的时候…
But I do know once the dying starts
我们这个脆弱的小团体马上就会四分五裂
this little psycho-fuck family of ours is gonna rip itself apart.
强斯为何抖得这么厉害？
Ever wonder why Johns shakes like that?
你问他
Ask him.
问你的船员死前为何惨叫？
Ask why your crew pal had to scream so painfully before he died
(船身百分之百完整)
你究竟是什么？
So who are you really?
你不是警察？
You're not a cop, are you?
我没说我是警察
I never said I was, Carolyn.
你是没说
No, you didn't.
你也没说你有毒瘾
And you never said you were a hype either.
早晨你喝咖啡 我打吗啡不行吗？
You have a little caffeine in the morning, and I have a little morphine. So what?
你每天有两个早晨 幸运儿
Here you got two mornings every day. Wow, were you born lucky.
这不是问题 除非你要…
It's not a problem unless you're gonna make it.
你让欧文斯死掉 这件事便有问题
No, it becomes a problem when you let Owens die like that!
你有足够药物使全队人昏迷
You have enough drugs here to knock out a fucking mule team.
欧文已经死了
Owens was already dead.
他的大脑尚未会意而已
His brain just hadn't caught on to the fact.
你还有什么秘密没告诉我的？
Is there anything else I should know about you, Johns?
你知道 我让你掌握我们的命运
You know, I... I'm letting you roll the dice on our lives.
那是不合理的
It is not unreasonable...
感觉得到吗？
Do you feel that?
那是我第一次跟瑞迪接触
That's my first run-in with Riddick.
他在这里留了个疤 然后消失不见了
He went for the sweet spot and missed.
他们把刀片留在那里
They had to leave a piece of the shiv in there, Carolyn,
我感到它在压迫着我的脊髓
and I can feel it pressing against the cord.
所以我才会神经紧张
So maybe the care and feeding of my nerve endings is my business.
你本来可以做些什么 但你没有去做
It's just that you could've done something, and you didn't.
先顾你自己的事吧 卡洛琳
Well, look to thing own ass first, right, Carolyn?
船长 船长
Captain! Captain!
我不是船长
I'm not your fucking Captain.
我看到什么了？
What do my eyes see?
如果要去坠毁的船上搬东西
If we need anything from the crash ship, I suggest we kick on.
坐太阳能车
That sand cat's solar.
瑞迪呢？
Where's Riddick?
由他去 他不会等我们
Leave him. He wouldn't wait for us.
还以为你走了
Thought we lost you.
强斯
Johns.
你干什么？
Hey! Where are you going?
拿几样东西 马上就好
I've just gotta get a couple things.
你不会丢下我吧？
You wouldn't leave without me, would you?
有多少？
How many are there?
好漂亮
Beautiful.
天啊
Allah.
各位 我建议
People. Just a suggestion.
你们应该逃走
Perhaps you should free.
我们走
Let's go.
快跑
Come on, run.
杰克
Jack.
快走
Come on.
上车
Get in.
趴下
Get down.
不
No...
夏沙 留在原地
Shazza! Stay there.
- 伏下 伏下  - 回来
- Stay down, Shazza! Just stay down!  - Come back here!
- 夏沙  - 伏下
- Shazza  - stay down!
拜托 我们应该进去
Please, I really think we should go inside.
一定要进去 关上门
We have to be inside. We have to close the door.
我们走 走
Come on, let's go!
雷克 怎么回事 又怎么了
What is it, Riddick? What is it now?
正如我说的
Like I said.
你们要怕的不是我
It ain't me you gotta worry about.
她应该趴下 那就没事了
She should've stayed down. If she only would've stayed down.
她没事 死不了
She'd be okay. She wouldn't have died.
你记得那坟场吗？
You remember the boneyard?
一定都是遭这些东西的毒手
These just might be the fuckers that killed every living thing on this planet.
我们怎么办？
What are we gonna do now?
只有这些灯光？就这些？
Are these the only lights we have? Is this everything?
不 地上有手电筒 只是找不到
No, there's a cutting torch on the floor here somewhere. I just can't find it.
安静 拜托大家安静
Quiet! Please, everyone.
他们为何要发出这样的声音？
Why do they make that sound?
这大概是他们看东西的方法
Perhaps it's the way they see... With sound, reelecting back...
可能船身有裂口
It could be a breach in the hull. I don't know.
弶斯 你有枪 你去吧
Come on, Johns. You got the big gauge.
我宁可射玻璃 你怎么不自己去？
I'd rather piss glass. Why don't you go fucking check?
这里我一秒钟也不留
I'm not staying here for one more second.
你要上哪去？
Where are you going? Hey!
巴里斯
Paris!
让他坐下
Sit him down.
你根本不知外面有什么东西？
You don't know what's out there.
我知道里面有什么
I know what's in here.
快点
Hurry.
我们困在狭窄的地方 真可恶
Now we're trapped in a much smaller space. I hate this!
真是不巧
Extremely bad timing.
不要跑
Just don't run.
瑞迪？
Riddick?
不要让火熄掉
Don't stop burning.
拿这个
Take this.
- 拿这个  - 好
- Take this.  - Okay.
哈山 哈山呢？
Hassan. Where is Hassan?
它还活着？
Is it alive?
光好像会灼伤它
It's like the light is scalding it.
光能伤它们 真的能伤它们
It hurts them. Light actually hurts them.
那是哈山？
Is that Hassan?
待会为他点根腊烛
We'll burn a candle for him later.
快 快离开这儿
Come on, let's get out of here.
我们有两支火炬 两个手电筒
So we've got one cutting torch we've got two handlights.
船上应该有可燃物
There's gotta be something we can rip out of the crash ship.
酒精含量超过45%都可燃
Spirits. Anything over 45 proof burns rather well.
你有几瓶酒？
How many bottles you got?
不知道 也许十瓶
I don't know. Maybe ten.
弶斯 你有照明弹？
Okay, Johns. You got some flares?
所以
So...
也许火光够用
Maybe we got enough light.
够什么用？
Enough for fucking what?
照原来的计划
We stick to the plan.
带四具电池回去就可以离开
We get the four cells back to the skiff. We're off this rock.
我真不想泼冷水
Look, I hate to ruin a beautiful theory with an ugly fact
但是太阳能车夜间开不动
but that sand cat is solar. It won't run at night.
把电池背回去
So we carry the cells.
拖回去都可以
We drag them, whatever it takes.
今夜吗？外面全是那些东西
You mean tonight? With all those things still out there?
这东西可撑多久？
All right, now how long can this last?
几个小时？最多一天
A few hours? A day, tops.
我觉得两个行星
I had the impression from the model
正在溶合…
the two planets were moving as one
届时便会不见天日
and there would be a lasting darkness.
这些太阳总要出来吧
These suns gotta come up some time.
如果这些东西怕光
And if these creatures are phobic about light,
我们就坐着等太阳出来
then we just sit tight, and we let the sun come up.
肯定有人提过
I'm sure somebody else said that.
关在样品室里
Locked inside that coring room.
我们要为每个人着想
We need to think about everybody now.
尤其是那个孩子
Especially the kid.
他在外面会怕成什么样？
How scared is this boy gonna be out there in the dark?
别利用他
Don't use him like that.
什么利用？
Like what?
拿他做借口 你自己害怕
As a smokescreen. You deal with your own fear.
你为何不闭嘴
Why don't you shut your fucking mouth for two seconds
我们能否想个不用集体自杀的计划
and let me come up with a plan that doesn't' involve mass suicide
我等你的办法
I'm waiting.
强斯 你有多重？
How much you weigh, Johns?
怎么了 卡洛琳？
What's it matter, Carolyn?
有多重？
How much?
大约79公斤
Around 79 kilos to be exact.
你就是79公斤的脓包
'Cause you're 79 kilos of gutless white meat
所以想不出好办法
and that's why you can't think of a better plan.
是这样吗？
Is that fucking right?
你上哪去？
Where you going?
这样解决不了问题
This solves nothing.
好
Okay.
它们怕光
They're afraid of our light.
所以不必太害怕
That means we don't have to be so afraid of them.
你有把握带我们摸黑回去？
And you are sure you can get us there? Even in the dark?
我不能 但他可以
No, I can't. But he can.
大家靠紧
Stay close...
等一下
Wait...
瑞迪？
Riddick?
看起来安全
Looks clear.
你说安全
You said "clear".
我说看起来安全
I said it "looks clear".
现在看起来如何？
Well, what's it look like now?
看起来安全
Looks clear.
我在前十步距离 照我的后面 别照眼睛
Be running about ten paces ahead. I want light on my back, but not in my eyes.
检查伤口 它们认得血的气味
And check your cuts. These bad boys know our blood now.
真的要硬闯？
Are we actually gonna do this?
我们靠拢 保持亮光
We stay together, we keep the light burning.
只要这样就可以通过
That's all we gotta do to live through this thing.
强斯 好了没有？
Are you ready Johns?
嗯
Mmm...
我们在浪费光源…
Look, we're just wasting light here.
把电池交给他
You give him the cells...
船也交给他 他会丢下你们
and the ship, and he'll leave you all out there to die.
他会丢下你们
He'll leave all of you.
我真不懂
I don't get it, Johns.
在你生命中难道没有值得珍惜的？
What is so goddam valuable in your life that you're wormed about losing?
难道一件也没有？
Is there anything at all?
除了过毒瘾？
Besides your next spike?
要紧跟着
You must stay close.
等一下
Wait.
杰克
Jack.
Jack!
这不可能
That can't be happening.
巴里斯
Paris!
回来
Get back here.
你要紧吗？
Are you all right?
这不可能
This can't be happening.
我应该死在法国
I was supposed to die in France.
我从没见过法国
I never ever saw France.
看到你没事真好
Well, it's good to see you're okay.
我真的不要知道
Do I even want to know?
快到了吗？
Are we getting close?
可以加快脚步吗？
Can we pick up the pace?
告诉我怎么回事
You want to tell me what the hell's going on.
又走回原路了
We crossed our own tracks.
怎么兜圈子？迷路了吗？
Why have we circled? Are we lost?
注意听
Listen.
- 这是哪里？- 你听
- Do you even know where we are?  - Listen!
前面是峡谷 让我想想
Canyon ahead. I circled once to buy some time to think.
我们该走了
I think we should go now.
我看走不了 那是死路
I don't know about that. That's death row up there.
尤其是女孩在流血
Especially with the girl bleeding.
什么？
What?
你胡说 她没有受伤
What the fuck you talking about? She's not cut.
不是她
Not her.
是她
Her.
你开玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
我以为反串男人会比较好
I just thought it'd be better if people took me for a guy.
这样他们就不会烦我
I thought they might leave me alone
- 免得骚扰  - 怎么不告诉我？
- instead of always messing with me.  - Why didn't you tell me?
对不起 亲爱的
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
你真的流血了？
Are you really bleeding?
你会丢下我的 所以我没说
You could left me at the ship, Fry. That's why I didn't say anything sooner.
它们一直盯着她
They've been nose-open for her even since we left
你没注意到它们嗜血
in case you haven't noticed, they go off blood.
这样行不通
Look, this is not gonna work.
我们得回去
We're gonna have to go back.
你说什么？
What did you say?
你叫我们出来当拉撬的狗
You're the one who got us out here in the first place and turned us into sled dogs.
我承认错了 回船去好吗？
I was wrong. I admit it. Can we just get back to the ship?
不知道 但这里有风 够空旷
I don't know. Carolyn. Nice breeze, wide open space...
我开始喜欢这里了
I'm starting to enjoy my fucking self out here!
你又嗑药了？语无伦次
Are you high again? Just listen to yourself, Johns.
不是 你说得对 怕什么
No, no. You're right, Carolyn. What's to be afraid of?
反正我活得无意义 由他去
My life's a steaming pile of meaningless shit anyhow. So I say mush on.
离峡谷才两百公尺 过了就好了
The canyon's only a couple of hundred meters, and after that it's skiff city.
所以鼓起勇气 别像个孩子一样 我们走
So why don't you butch up, stuff a cork in this fucking kid, and let's go.
她是船长 我们要听她的
She's the Captain! We should listen to her.
听她的？
Listen to her?
她曾经要牺牲我们
When she was so willing to sacrifice us all?
他在说什么？
What's he talking about?
说这些于事无补
This does not help us, Johns.
船坠毁之前…
During the crash...
她曾经想炸毁客舱
she tried to blow the whole passenger cabin.
炸死熟睡的我们
Tried to kill us in our sleep.
你闭嘴
Shut your mouth.
我们是牺牲品
We are fucking disposable.
- 他说什么？- 把我们当行尸
- What is he talking about?  - We're just walking ghosts to you.
你他妈闭嘴
Shut your fucking blowhole.
好 很好
Fine. Fine.
你说对了
You've made your point.
我们都被吓倒
We can all be scared.
卡洛琳 现在你有多重？
Oh, Carolyn. How much do you weigh now?
由体轻的人走前面
The verdict's in. The light moves forward.
不是人人都能走到
Ain't all of us gonna make it.
你才意识到？
Just realize that?
我们剩六个 假如走到峡谷
Six of us left. If we could make it through the canyon
只牺牲一个人够好了吧？
and lose just one, that'd be quite a feat, huh?
不是我死都很好
Not if I'm the one.
把你列入五个活口
Well, what if you're one of five?
我在听
I'm listening.
他们在上面干什么？
What are they doing up there?
大概是谈去峡谷的事
They're talking about the canyon, I suppose.
商量怎样通过峡谷
How to get us through.
军医把伤患分类决定谁生谁死
Battlefield doctors decide who lives and dies, it's called triage.
我说这是谋杀
Kept calling it "murder" when I did it.
管它是什么 你可以仿效
Either way I figure it's something you can grab onto.
玩牺牲游戏
Sacrifice play.
剁一具尸体丢在峡谷口
Hack up a body, leave it at the start of the canyon.
当做诱饵
Like a bucket of bart.
拖着走 扎撬的绳子还有多
Trawl with it. You got extra cable on the sled.
保持尸体离我们四五十尺远
We drag the body 40, 50 feet behind us.
好主意
Nice embellishment.
不是喂它们 只是引开它们
Well, I don't wanna feed 'em I just wanna keep 'em off our scent.
找谁做诱饵？
So which one caught your eye?
不 不要看 你怎么搞的
No, no, don't look! Christ! What the hell's wrong with you?
伊曼 走慢一点
Imam, slow down.
离他们远一点
Just a little more space between us and them.
好了 废话少说
All right. Enough of this shit.
你对付那女孩 我挡住其他人
You do the girl and I'll keep the others off your back.
这对你不是难事吧？
It's not too big a job for you, is it?
也许用不着那么大的饵
I'm just wondering if we don't need a bigger piece of bait.
那么找谁？
Like who?
丢下撬 我们走
Leave the sled! Let's move!
我们走
Let's go.
有一个办法
One rule.
留在光里
Stay in the light.
记得那一刻
Remember that moment.
强斯 你不应该冒那次险
You should have never taken the chains off, Johns.
你以前很勇敢
You were one brave fuck before.
你是大恶人比利
You were Billy Bad-Ass.
那些锁链
The chains.
那霰弹枪
The gauge.
那警徽
The badge.
我曾经叫你杀我
I told you to ghost me.
回船去？
Back to the ship, huh?
挤在一起等光烧完
Just huddle together until the lights burn out?
走开
Get away from us.
直至你看不见那东西？
'Til you can't see what's eating you?
这就是你的计划？
That the big plan?
强斯呢？
Where's Johns?
你指哪一片？
Which half?
在这里大家都会完蛋
We're gonna lose everybody out here.
我们应该待在船上
We should have stayed at the ship.
他死得很快
He died fast.
如果有选择就应该出去
And if we have any choice about it, that's the way we should all go out.
不要为强斯哭 别害怕
Don't you cry for Johns. Don't you dare.
盲点
Blind spot.
一起祷告好吗？
Shall we pray together?
我跟其他人祷告过了
I have already prayed with the others.
可以减轻痛苦
It's painless.
- 没用的  - 你不相信神
- It's pointless.  - Because you do not believe in God
并不表示神不要你
does not mean God does not believe in you.
有人半辈子坐牢
Think someone can spend half their life in a slam
就不信神？
with a horse-bit in their mouth and not believe?
那些生下来
Think he could start out in some liquor store trash bin
就被丢在垃圾筒的人 不信神？
with an umbilical cord wrapped around his neck, and not believe?
你弄错了 大圣人
You got it all wrong, Holy Man.
我全然相信神
I absolutely believe in God.
我恨死那傢伙
And I absolutely hate the fucker.
不过他跟我们一道
He is with us, nonetheless.
你的人已死了两个
Two of your boys are already dead.
你还有几分信心？
How much faith do you have left, Father?
只有一条路
Only see one way.
那边 要离开岩石只有这条路
That way. It's the only way off this rock.
让女孩走在中间
Just keep the girl between you.
这些电池呢？
What about the cells?
我来拿
I'll take those.
快走
Move.
你真的赶得上？
Are you sure you can keep up?
走
Move.
不要往上看
Do not look up.
不要看上面
它们在自相残杀
They're killing each other.
走
Move!
往前走
Keep moving!
向前进
苏利曼
Sule!
瑞迪
Riddick!
等一下
Wait!
瑞迪
Riddick!
放开她
Get off her!
不要紧
It's okay.
不知道他在搞什么
Did not know who he was fucking with.
- 起来  - 苏利曼
- Get up.  - Suleman.
扶他起来 苏利曼 快
Come on, get him up. Sule, come on.
起来
Get up.
不好
Oh no.
你的神在哪里？
So where the hell's your God now?
瑞迪
Riddick!
快到了吗？
Are we close?
那边是什么情况？
Just tell me that the settlement is right there.
我们到不了
We can't make it.
苏利曼
Sule!
暂时躲在这里
Hide here. Now.
他怎么还在那边？
Why is he still out there?
他不会回来了吗？
He's not coming back, is he?
这是最后的了
That's the last I could find.
强烈的求生欲
Strong survival instinct.
我佩服这种女人
I admire that in a woman.
我答应他们带更多的光回去
I promised them that we would go back with more light.
是吗？
Did you?
你害怕吗？
Are you afraid?
我害怕？
Me afraid?
好了 瑞迪
Come on, Riddick.
你总该有点人性吧？
There's got to be some part of you that wants to rejoin the human race.
老实说我不知何谓人性
Truthfully, I wouldn't know how.
那就多给些光 我带回去
Then just give me more light for them. I'll go back by myself.
好的
Okay.
给你
There you go.
请你跟我回去
Please just come with me.
我有更好的主意 你跟我走
I got a better idea. Come with me.
你在利用我 我知道
You're fucking with me. I know you are.
你了解我
You know I am.
你一点也不了解我
You don't know anything about me.
我会丢下你不管
I will leave you here.
进来吧
Step inside.
我不能走
I can't.
你当然能走
Sure you can.
我不能
I can't.
来 我拉你一把
Here, I'll make it easy on you.
握住我的手
Take my hand.
来呀 走呀
Come on. Come on.
没人会怪你保自己的命
No one's gonna blame you. Save yourself, Carolyn.
来呀
Come on.
走
这才对嘛
That's it.
这才乖
Good girl.
现在
Now, you...
你给我听着 我是船长
You listen to me. I'm the Captain of this ship.
我决不留任何人给那些怪物
And I am not leaving anyone on this rock with those fucking things,
不惜一切…
even if it means.
把刀子拿开
Get that thing off my neck.
闭嘴
Shut up!
你愿意为他们死？
You'd die for them?
我愿意一试
I would try for them.
你没回答我
You didn't answer me.
是 我愿意
Yes, I would, Riddick.
我愿意为他们死
I would. I would die for them.
真有意思
How interesting.
毫无疑问
Never had a doubt.
有谁没准备好？
Anyone not ready for this?
我的神在那边 瑞迪先生
There is my God, Mr. Riddick.
不要停 不要停
Don't stop...
快 走 走
Come on! Move! Move!
你知道路
You know the way.
上去 快上去
On board! Come on. Get on.
卡洛琳
Carolyn.
来 来
Come...
等一下
Wait.
瑞迪
Riddick?
好 抱住我
Okay, hold onto me.
我们离开这里 我抓住你了
We're gonna get outta here. Okay, I got you.
快 起来 瑞迪 起来
Come on, Riddick! Get up! Get up!
我为他们死 不为你 走
I said I'd die for them, not you. Let's move.
快到了 加油
We're nearly there. Come on.
好耶
All right.
不要为我
Not for me.
Not for me!
欠很多祷告要补
With so much prayer to make up for,
真不知从何补起
I scarcely know where to begin.
我知道从哪开始
I know where I'd start.
瑞迪 你干什么？
Riddick, what are you doing?
我们赶快走好吗？
Can we just get the hell out of here now?
我们不能走
We can't leave
没有道别
without saying goodnight
有很多问题 不管遇到谁
A lot of questions, whoever we run into.
可能是一艘医疗船
Could even be a merc ship.
我们怎么交代你的身份？
So what the hell do we tell them about you?
就说瑞迪死了
Tell them Riddick's dead.
死在那个星球上了
He died somewhere on that planet.